McLaren, Eugene; Papers ua902.031
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Eugene McLaren Papers
1940-2001
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
McLaren, Eugene
ua902.031
7.8 cubic ft.
The Eugene McLaren Papers document his academic pursuits as well as research he conducted while on the faculty at the University at Albany.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted, with the exception of a small number of select files noted on the inventory.
Acquisition Information
The papers were donated to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Eugene McLaren over the course of several years during the early 2000s.
Biographical Sketch
Eugene H. McLaren was born in the 1920s and began attending the New York State College for Teachers (now the University at Albany) in 1941. His studies were interrupted during World War II when he transferred to New York University from 1943-1944, earning a certificate from the Air Force Meteorology program. He returned to Albany in 1946, earning his bachelor's degree in Science and Mathematics in 1948 and a master's degree in Chemistry in 1949. Next McLaren went to the University of Basel in Switzerland to study Advanced German and Chemistry until 1950. He returned to the United States to serve as an instructor of Chemistry at the New York State College for Teachers, and then studied at Washington University in St. Louis from 1952 to 1955, securing a doctorate in Physical Chemistry. While pursuing his doctorate, McLaren worked each summer in the Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory in New Mexico.
Upon earning his Ph. D., McLaren returned to Albany to become an Associate Professor of Chemistry at the New York State College for Teachers from 1955-1957. After a three year break as a Senior Research Chemist at the Pan American Petroleum Corporation in Tulsa, Oklahoma, he returned to Albany to become a full Professor of Chemistry in 1960, a position that he held until his retirement in 1989. Upon his return, McLaren also became a Professor of Science and Chairman for the Department of Earth and Atmospheric Sciences until 1962. McLaren then became a Chairman for the Division of Science and Mathematics until 1968. In 1968, McLaren was appointed Associate Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences for a year; along with becoming a member of the Board of Directors for the Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists. He then became a Research Associate of the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center in 1969. McLaren was also a University Fellow and Research Associate at the Max-Planck-Institute for Chemistry in Mainz, Germany from 1969-1970. McLaren would return to Germany as a Visiting Professor at the University of Frankfurt from 1984-1985.
During his career, McLaren was a member of several professional societies, including the American Chemical Society, the American Meteorological Society, the Society of Sigma Xi, the Geochemical Society, the New York Academy of Science, and the Air Pollution Control Association, and was a fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. He also worked alongside several well-known meteorologists such as Vincent Schaefer and Bernard Vonnegut, and conducted research throughout his career.
Scope and Contents
This collection covers Eugene McLaren’s professional activities while employed at the University at Albany, both administrative and research related. The papers are predominantly limited to only Albany, there are few records of his involvements in Germany with the exceptions of the Wuerzburg Study Abroad Program and U.S.-European research collaborations.
The bulk of the papers date from the early 1960s to the late 1980s, covering McLaren's tenure as Professor of Chemistry at the University. Any documents outside of that range are either research materials or pertain to one of his colleagues. The collection is split into two series, one for his research and one for his academic papers. McLaren's research work involved collaboration with European colleagues and attending conferences, as well as participating in research expeditions. Correspondences from these interactions are included in the collection, along with research notes from various projects. Of most note is work regarding Project Cirrus and strong acid formation in fog, with some additional findings recorded during the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center's annual Yellowstone Research Expedition.
As part of his academic service, McLaren was a member of a number of small committees that had a very wide variety of purposes ranging from the Alumni Day Committee to the Wuerzburg Study Abroad Committee. Materials from these committees is found within the collection. Of interest also may be several booklets and papers documenting the opening of the Uptown Campus of the University at Albany, and publications of the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center.
For related materials, please see the following collections held by the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collection & Archives: Atmospheric Sciences Research Center Records (UA-450), which includes many publications and articles issued by the ASRC, Duncan Blanchard Papers (UA-902.065), Raymond Falconer Papers (UA-902.014), Bernard Vonnegut Papers (UA-902.068) and Vincent J. Schaefer Papers (UA-902.010).
Separated Materials
The archivist transferred two monographs: Heterogeneous Atmospheric Chemistry edited by David R. Schryer and Field and Laboratory Guide for Ecology written by Paul C. Lemon to the book division of Special Collections. These will be cataloged and included at a later date in the University Library Catalog.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Universities and Colleges--New York (State)--Administration; Education, Higher--New York (State); Precipitation (Meteorology)--Modification--Research; Correspondence; Scientific reports; Memorandums; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; McLaren, Eugene; State University of New York at Albany; State University of New York. Atmospheric Sciences Research Center
- Administrative Material, 1940-2001; Undated; 1; 4.6 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of McLaren’s administrative papers. It is predominantly composed of memorandums and correspondences documenting his involvement with a large number of different committees throughout his tenure at the University Albany. Most notable in size are the applications for the Husted Award, an annual award granted to the most outstanding undergraduate senior in science, which he was involved with from 1977 until his retirement in 1989. This series also contains his general papers, some teaching materials, and several booklets on the history of the University at Albany’s Uptown Campus.
  - Acid Rain Conference, 1981; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 1)
  - African-American Program Committee, 1969; 1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 2)
  - Alumni Day Committee, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 3)
  - Alumni Day Talk Notes, 1963; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 4)
  - ASRC 25th Anniversary Dinner, 1986; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 5)
  - ASRC Administrative Correspondence, 1961-1965; 1969-1972; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 6)
  - ASRC Administrative Correspondence, 1972; 1982-1988; 1990; 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 7)
  - ASRC Director Recruit, 1965; 1996; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 8)
  - ASRC Establishment and Additions, 1961-1962; 1994 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 9)
  - ASRC Progress Report, 1964; 1967; 1969 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 10)
  - Awards Committee, Chemistry Department, 1960; 1984; 1986-1987; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 11)
  - Awards (Departmental) for 1987, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 12)
  - Awards (Departmental) for 1988, 1985-1988; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 13)
  - Dr. Banks' Teaching Professorship Award, 1963-1965; 1985-1989; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 14)
  - Biochemist's Meetings, 1971; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 15-16)
  - Bulletin of Atomic Scientists, 1972-1975; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 17)
  - By-Law Committee, College of Science and Mathematics, 1969; 1976-1977; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 18)
  - Calenders, 1961-1965 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 19)
  - Campus Dedication Committee, 1967-1969; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 20)
  - Castillo, Raymond Correspondence, 1972; 1979 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 21)
  - Castillo, Raymond Correspondence, 1980-1982; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 22)
  - Chemistry Professor Recruitment, 1961; 1963-1964; 1967; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 23)
  - Cheng, Roger Correspondence, 1980; 1985; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 24)
  - Committee on Developmental Science, 1964; 1971; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 25)
  - Committee on Developmental Science, 1972; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 26)
  - Committee on Teacher Evaluation, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 27)
  - Commencement Ceremony, 1954; 1983-1984; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 28)
  - Commencement Committee, 1980-1984; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 29)
  - Commencement Marshals, 1982-1984; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 30)
  - Community University Day, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 31)
  - Conference Booklets, 1961; 1965 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1965 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1980; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1989 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1994; 2001 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 5)
  - Council - College of Math and Science, 1976-1978 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 6)
  - Creativity, 1965-1967 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1959-1962; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 8)
  - Department Development Proposal, Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 9)
  - Distinguished Doctoral Thesis Award, 1986 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 10)
  - Division Papers, 1968; 1970 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 11)
  - Division Budget, 1966-1968; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 12)
  - Division Meetings, 1968-1970; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 13)
  - Droessler, Earl Correspondence, 1964; 1966; 1967 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 14)
  - Early Warning System, 1987 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 15)
  - Edison Celebration, 1974; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 16)
  - Educational Policies Council, 1967-1969; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 17)
  - Energy Conference, 1971; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 18)
  - Environmental Studies Planning Committee, 1977-1978; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 19)
  - Faculty Nominating Committee, 1976-1978; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 20)
  - General Education Program Review, 1971; 1987-1988; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 21)
  - Government Research Service Center, 1976-1977; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 22)
  - Graduate Admissions Committee, Chemistry Department, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 23)
  - Higher Education Booklets, 1958; 1968; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 24)
  - Hudson Valley Community College Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 25)
  - Husted Applications for 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 26)
  - Husted Applications for 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 27)
  - Husted Applications for 1978 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 28)
  - Husted Applications for 1979, Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 29)
  - Husted Applications for 1980, 1979-1981; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 30)
  - Husted Applications for 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 31)
  - Husted Applications for 1982 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 32)
  - Husted Applications for 1983, 1982-1983; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 33)
  - Husted Applications for 1984, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 34)
  - Husted Applications for 1985, Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 35)
  - Husted Applications for 1986, 1976; 1981; 1985-1986; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 36)
  - Husted Applications for 1987 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 37)
  - Husted Applications for 1988 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 38)
  - Husted Applications for 1989 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 39)
  - Husted Fellowship Winners, 1960-1969; 1971-1989; 1999; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 40)
  - Institute of Man and Science, 1967-1968; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 1)
  - Kroneis, W. Correspondence, 1988-1990; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 2)
  - Library Council, 1978-1979 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 3)
  - Lightning Detection Special Committee, 1984; 1987-1988; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 4)
  - Loomis School Atmospheric Sciences Center, 1960 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 5)
  - McLaren, Eugene General Papers, 1961-1969; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 6)
  - McLaren, Eugene General Papers, 1970-1979; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 7)
  - McLaren, Eugene General Papers, 1980-1992; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 8)
  - McLaren, Eugene Retirement Party, 1989 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 9)
  - Middle States Association Evaluation Team, 1963; 1966; 1970-1976; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 10)
  - Natural Sciences Institute, Final Report for 1963-1965 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 11)
  - North Eastern Regional Meeting, 1976; 1985-1987; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 12)
  - North Eastern Regional Meeting, 1988-1990; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 13)
  - Oneonta, 1978; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 14)
  - An Outline of Science, 1940 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 15)
  - Lemon, Paul C. Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 16)
  - Pearlmutter, William Correspondence, 1966; 1973-1975; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 17)
  - Peterssen, Sverre Correspondence, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 18)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Report, 1968-1969 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 19)
  - Pollution Talk, 1967-1968; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 20)
  - Program Development Information, 1955; 1957; 1963-1966; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 21)
  - Quantasorb Instrument Correspondence, 1982; 1989; 1991; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 22)
  - Recommendations, 1951; 1968; 1973-1976 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 23)
  - Recommendations, 1978-1984; 1987-1989; 1992 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 24)
  - Schaefer, Vincent J. Biographical, 1947; 1958-1959; 1962-1969; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 25)
  - Schaefer, Vincent J. Biographical, 1970-1974; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 26)
  - Schaefer, Vincent J. Biographical, 1984-1989 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 27)
  - Schaefer, Vincent J. Biographical, 1990-1996; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 28)
  - Schaefer, Vincent J. Dutch Barn Research, 1992; 1996; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 29)
  - Science Development Plan, 1963; 1965-1968; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 1)
  - Science Education, 1952; 1956-1957; 1962; 1965 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 2)
  - Science and the Future of Human Affairs, 1968-1970; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 3)
  - The Scientific Revolution Conference, 1967-1968; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 4)
  - Sigma Xi, 1969-1971; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 5)
  - Space Committee, 1982-1986; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 6)
  - Space Committee 1987-1988, Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 7)
  - Space Committee 1988-1989, 1987-1988; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 8)
  - Special Committee on Undergraduate Education 1966-1967, Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 9)
  - Special Committee on Undergraduate Education, 1968; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 10)
  - Spencer Award, 1987-1988 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 11)
  - State Education Department, 1966 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 12)
  - State University General, 1964; 1966-1967 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 13)
  - SUNY Albany Executive Committee, 1979-1980; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 14)
  - SUNY Albany Booklets, 1961 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 15)
  - SUNY Albany Booklets, 1964-1965 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 16)
  - SUNY Albany Booklets, 1966-1967 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 17)
  - SUNY Albany Booklets, 1968; 1983 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 18)
  - SUNY Albany Booklets, Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 19)
  - SUNY Albany Campus Academic Plan, 1968-1975 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 20)
  - SUNY Albany Campus History, 1948; 1966-1969; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 21)
  - SUNY Albany Campus History, 1970-1971; 1975; 1979; 1983; 1987-1989 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 22)
  - Student Science Journal, 1965-1966 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 23)
  - Teaching Materials, Space Time Sc 201, 1952; 1963-1967; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 24)
  - Teaching Materials, Sc 201 Environment, 1962; 1964; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 25)
  - Teaching Materials, 2nd Law of Thermodynamics, Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 26)
  - Teaching Materials, Slide Material Ch 121, 1973; 1977; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 27)
  - Teaching Materials, Lecture Slides, 2nd Law of Thermodynamics and Gibbs Free Energy Ch 121, 1965; 1973; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 28)
  - Tenure Committee, Faculty-Student, 1966-1968; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 1)
  - Tieszen Scholarship, 1966 (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 2)
  - Travel Papers, General, 1966-1968; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 3)
  - Unified Science, 1956; 1965-1968; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 4)
  - University-Industry Committee for Applied Science, 1980-1981; 1986-1987; 1990; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 5)
  - University Organization, 1966-1969; 1971; 1983; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 6)
  - Vonnegut, Bernard, 1946; 1997; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 7)
  - Weather Modification Conference Participants, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 8)
  - Whitney, James Correspondence, 1967-1968; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 9)
  - Wuerzburg Study Abroad Program, 1964; 1967-1968; Undated (Box 5 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 10)
  - Wuerzburg Study Abroad Program, 1970-1973; 1987-1988; Undated (Box 6 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 1)
  - Wuerzburg Study Abroad Program Committee, 1979-1984; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 6 (1-Administrative Material), Folder 2)
- Research Material, 1949-1990; Undated; 2; 3.2 cubic ft.
  This series consists of McLaren’s research papers. Most prominent is his work on strong acid formation in fog, research conducted from 1983 to 1986. Also included are notes from various conferences he attended, Atmospheric Sciences Research Center publications, papers regarding research trips to Yellowstone National Park along with Whiteface Mountain and Europe, and his involvement with Project Cirrus, a weather modification program conducted by General Electric in conjunction with the United States military.
  - Acid Rain Conference, 1980-1981; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 1)
  - Acid Rain Study Proposal and Grant Application, 1980; 1982 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 2)
  - Aerosol Paper, 1970-1971; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 3)
  - Aerosol Global Air Quality Pattern, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 4)
  - Airborne Cloud Water Collecting System, ASRC Publication, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 5)
  - Air Pollution, Atmosphere Modification, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 6)
  - Ammonium Sulfate in the Atmosphere, ASRC Publication, 1973; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 7)
  - Annual Air Division Report, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 8)
  - ASRC Reports, 1964 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 9)
  - ASRC 30th Anniversary Research Report, 1991 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 10)
  - CACR Symposium Abstracts, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 11)
  - Catalysis Conference, 1981; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 12)
  - Catalysis Project, 1962; 1980; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 13)
  - Catalysis Proposal, 1981; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 14)
  - Cloud Chemistry and Meteorological Research at Whiteface Mountain, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 15)
  - Chemical Precipitation Internal Report, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 16)
  - Condensation Nuclei, Landsberg, Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 17)
  - Condensation Process, 1975-1976; 1980; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 18)
  - Condensation Physics, Aerosols, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 19)
  - Corfu, Greece Trip, 1983; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 20)
  - Desert Research Institute University of Nevada, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 21)
  - Discussion, Conclusion, and Interpretations [Acid Rain], Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 22)
  - Effects of Carbon Monoxide, ASRC Publication, Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 23)
  - Energy Conservation, ASRC Publication, 1979; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 24)
  - European Programs, 1982-1984; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 25)
  - Fog Proposal, Historical with FISBAT, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 26)
  - Fog Proposal, Initial Work, 1981; 1983-1984; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 27)
  - Fog Proposal, International Materials, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 28)
  - Fog Proposal, NSF, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 29)
  - Fog Proposal, NSF, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Material), Folder 30)
  - Fog Proposal, NSF, 1987; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Material), Folder 1)
  - Fog Proposal, NSF, 1988-1989; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Material), Folder 2)